#### Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/ abhilashanigam (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

Agile Methodologies
ServiceNow Project Management
Jira

### Certifications

LOMA 281, 291 - Insurance Fundamentals Leading SAFe Agilist

Honors-Awards

On The Spot Award
CLP Faculty Award
TCS Excellence Award

# Abhilasha Nigam

Agile Project Manager India

# Summary

Senior IT professional with 18+ years of rich experience in top IT Industry organizations.

More than 12 years experience in Project Management and Program Management.

A Certified SAFe Agilist and Certified SCRUM Master,my key skills & experience lies in Agile Consulting, Agile and Digital Transformation, Agile Coaching & Mentoring, SCRUM delivery & Process Improvement.

Domain specialization - Banking & Insurance(BFSI),Retail eCommerce.

Education: Post-graduate with Masters in Computer Application(MCA) and MBA in International Business.

Certifications: Leading SAFe Agilist, Certified Scrum Master, FLMI Level 1 - LOMA 281 & 291.

Technical Background: Agile (SCRUM/SAFe frameworks), Digital & Cloud Technology (Microsoft Azure), Open Source CMS (Alfresco ECM, Drupal WCM, Liferay Portal, MS Sharepoint, Office 365),Java & J2EE.

Self-driven leader experienced in leading large teams with excellent analytical, communication, networking & collaboration skills.

# Experience

Wipro
Agile Project Manager/ Scrum Master
July 2022 - Present (1 year 2 months)
Mumbai

Managing Agile delivery & implementation of ServiceNow Transformation project in SAFe SCRUM Agile model. As Agile PM/Scrum Master primary responsibilities include setting up agile delivery process, best practices

and processes across workstreams, managing SCRUM teams, driving sprint ceremonies, co-ordinating with stakeholders; status reporting, metrics dashboarding, project management and team management.

Tata Consultancy Services
Agile Program Manager
October 2020 - July 2022 (1 year 10 months)
Mumbai, Maharashtra, India

Worked as Product Owner & Program Manager for Cloud & Al Teams of leading international accounts. Key focus being development of digital and cloud capabilities on Microsoft Azure Cloud; enhancing operations through DevOps automation, modernization & digitization of legacy application and services.

Tata Consultancy Services Limited 2 years 9 months

Agile Project Manager July 2018 - October 2019 (1 year 4 months) Gurgaon, India

In my current role as Agile Project Manager,I manage 2 application teams directly handling requirements management, Agile implementation, client and stakeholder interactions. A Leading SAFe Agilist and Certified Scrum Master,I have expertise in Agile transformation, mentoring and coaching.

I bring to the table rich experience in Project/Program Management,Business Analysis & Open Source Presales.

Business Analyst/PM,BFSI February 2017 - June 2018 (1 year 5 months) Gurgaon

Working for a leading UK Bank as a Sr. Business Analyst/PM in an individual contributor, customer-facing role wherein I work with business owners to capture new requirements in Agile, Cloud and Digital Re-enigineering space. I drive the Impact Analysis, requirement documentation, scoping and solution design by co-ordinating with various platform teams and architects. As a Business PM, I also manage project setup, scheduling, budgeting, governance and status reporting to UK Delivery Management for multiple projects.

Tata Consultancy Services Limited 3 years 10 months

Sr. Business Analyst, Digital Ecommerce COE, Retail October 2015 - December 2016 (1 year 3 months) Page 2 of 4 Mumbai Area, India

As Business Analyst in the Digital Business Process COE team,I worked directly with top US Retail client on their Digital eCommerce agile projects. I'm responsible for managing and designing new business requirements through Sharepoint/JIRA/Visio; conducting requirement discussions with multiple stakeholders & end-users; creating BRDs and proposals; managing small projects' programme and working with senior client business managers on new initiatives.

Presales Solution Architect - Opensource CMS March 2013 - September 2015 (2 years 7 months) Mumbai

As Open Source CMS COE Lead, established and managed the CMS COE team in Lucknow - handling presales support and technical consulting for opensource Content Management platforms like Alfresco, Drupal and Liferay. Responsible for opensource cms evangelization & adoption in TCS; Architecting technical solutions and providing end-to-end presales support for RFP/RFIs/Proactive Proposals for multiple ISUs and geographies; Managing India partner relationships for technologies supported.

Conducted Presentations/Workshops for Clients, Roadshows and Training sessions in collaboration with partners and TCS accounts, provided Technical Advisory and mentoring to opensource projects in cms domain.

Infosys Ltd.
Project Manager
July 2010 - March 2013 (2 years 9 months)

Worked as a Project Manager in Banking and Hi-Tech domain, on Java-J2EE & web projects, heading large distributed teams across multiple locations. Involved in presales, business analysis, technical consulting, requirement analysis, estimations, design, implementation, project & process management, training and recruitment activities.

Responsible for Client Relationship, Stakeholder Management & Resource Management.

Completed PM Lite(Project Management) and J2EE Certifications in Infosys.

HCL Technologies Ltd.
BA-Team Lead
February 2008 - July 2010 (2 years 6 months)

Primarily worked in Retail domain(eCommerce and Publishing) as well as Telecom domain.

Handled Business analyst and lead role for design, devleopment of SDLC projects.

Extensive experience in conducting DPA & other QA activities for multiple Webtech teams.

Holding e-Certifications in CMMi and OMS.

Birlasoft Ltd.

Software Developer

February 2005 - February 2008 (3 years 1 month)

Worked as Business Analyst and Java/J2EE developer in Finance/

Reinsurance domain.

Certified Process Champion

## Education

Institute of Management Education, Ghaziabad Master of Computer Applications (MCA) · (2002 - 2005)

Sikkim Manipal University of Health, Medical and Technological Sciences

Master of Business Administration (M.B.A.), International Business & Project Management · (2011 - 2013)

University of Lucknow

B.Sc. Computer Science · (1998 - 2001)

La Martiniere Girls' College, Lucknow I.S.C, Science, English · (1998)

Page 4 of 4